

Experienced working with Core Java, Collections & Design Patterns|Proficient in technologies such as Rest web services, elastic search, Cassandra, maven, GIT and Communication Skills.



Current Designation: Senior Java Developer Total Experience: 6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Merck Notice Period: Currently Serving Notice Period

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Web Services, Elastic Search, Cassandra, Core Java, Advanced Java, rest api, Collection Framework, Data

Structures, OOP, SQL, Github, Jenkins

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Summary

Experience in developing Restful APIs using JAX-RS and JSON.

Design, develop and maintain eCommerce sites for various locales

Experience in writing JUnit Test cases for Restful API of application to test and

and debug the application.

Experience in Elastic Search.

Experience in working in Java 8 Lambda Expressions, Stream API etc.

Knowledgeable in API modeling languages and annotation (Swagger Documentation),

and Lombok Framework.

Extensive Object-Oriented Development OOP experience.

Experience in Core java, Collection framework.

Experience in Exceptions Handling, String Handling, Wrapper classes and serialization.

Experience in writing Basic SQL queries using RDBMS.

Experience in Hibernate, Spring MVC.

Strong working Experience in using source code/version control system Git BitBucket.

Having good familiarity in using JIRA tool for bug tracking, issue tracking, and project management and also Jenkins tools for continuous integration.

Work Experience

Merck as Senior Java Developer

Aug 2018 to Till Date

This project is aimed to develop e-commerce platform which is distributed and scalable that allows the end users to view/search/order products from this application. It has ability to handle B2C and B2B business models, its customizable as per organization requirements, Includes user management, and customer support, order processing etc.

Created new Rest web service resources and modified the existing web services to support the front-end and back-end functionality.

Created and executed JUnit test cases for Restful API of application.

Created web services for full text search platform using NoSQL Elastic search engine, allowing for much faster, more scalable and more intuitive user searches for our database of spas worldwide.

Used maven as build management tool.

Developed lookup tables and views to speed up queries.

Efficiently handled periodic exporting of data into Elastic search.

To Fixed the Issues reported by System Testing Team and UAT Team.

Involved in analysis and design phases of Software Development Life Cycle.

Environment: Linux, Java1.8, Cassandra, eclipse, F5, Postman, Jenkins, wild fly, Bit bucket,

JIRA.

Technologies: Rest API using JAX-RS, Java 1.8, Cassandra, Elastic Search

Accenture as Application Development Analyst Nov 2014 to Aug 2018

Java Developer

Education

UG: B.Sc (maths and physics) from BRD College Duddhi in 2010

PG: MCA (Computers) from IET-Lucknow in 2014

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Eclipse IDE		2020	4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
TOAD		2018	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Unix/Linux	Centos	2020	4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Basic SQL			
RDBMS			
CORE JAVA			
ALGORITHMS			
postman		2020	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Hibernate, Spring MVC		2017	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Rest API, JSON			
Hibernate			
Elastic Search		2020	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Maven, putty			
Toad For Oracle, DataStax			
Bit Bucket, Tortoise SVN		2020	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Apache Tomcat & Wildfly		2020	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
JIRA		2020	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
WINDOWS, LINUX	centos	2020	4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient			
Hindi	Expert			

Projects

Project Title: AT & T:- YTR

Client: AT&T

Duration: Oct 2016 - Till Date Nature of Employment: Full Time Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: Working as a java developer.

Project Title: Disney Client: Walt Disney World

Duration: Jan 2015 - Aug 2016 Nature of Employment: Full Time

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: Worked as a java developer and a wiremock developer.

Affirmative Action

Category: OBC - non-creamy

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Countries: India

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary

Employment Status: Full time